<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on PEILING SONG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on PEILING SONG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tree Species Classification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project is to classify dominant tree species across Germany by leveraging satellite image time series. Forest management practices benefit from knowledge of species distribution, which supports site-adapted tree selection and climate-resilient forest planning. Tree species labels in the TreeSatAI dataset are organised hierarchically (leaf type, genus, species), allowing us to develop classification methods that exploit this structure to improve model performance. We integrate Sentinel-2 multi-spectral imagery (10 spectral bands, 5 vegetation indices) into a data processing pipeline that extracts monthly composites (March–October 2022) and generates 5×5 pixel patches for each reference point. We trained and evaluated five classification models: Random Forest, XGBoost, Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN), Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN), and Transformer architectures.Hierarchical labels (L1, L2) significantly improved accuracy both traditional machine learning and deep learning models(CNN, RNN). Furthermore, data augmentation with rotation and translation enhanced the generalisation ability of deep learning models. Among all methods, XGBoost achieved the highest test accuracy (83.6%)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Building Digital Model Reconstruction Using a Robotic Agent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The project is designed to capture and process real-time spatial data of the built environment by integrating advanced sensing technologies, such as LiDAR and an RGB-D camera, onto a robotic platform. These sensors work in unison to collect high-quality spatial and visual data, which is then seamlessly streamed using the Robot Operating System (ROS). ROS facilitates the efficient handling of sensor data, enabling real-time processing through advanced algorithms that reconstruct the environment&amp;rsquo;s geometry with precision. By combining robotics, state-of-the-art sensors, advanced point cloud processing techniques, and real-time computation, the project aims to provide accurate and dynamic spatial mapping solutions, offering a robust foundation for applications in fields such as architecture, urban planning, and autonomous navigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Ambient Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is about developing an Indoor Ambient Monitoring system to manage and visualize human comfort relevant environmental parameters like temperature, humidity, illuminance, noise level, CO2 concentration, and others in an indoor environment. Further, the task is to study an insight on LoRaWAN Indoor Network Coverage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj2-1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xmruuu.github.io/25SS_IoT_Indoor-Ambient-Monitoring/&#34;&gt;Open Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The system architecture is divided into hardware and software components. On the hardware side, multiple indoor environmental sensors (measuring CO, PM2.5, temperature, humidity, etc.) transmit data via LoRa using the CayenneLPP encoding format through a LoRaWAN gateway to IoT cloud platforms such as TTN and SWM. On the software side, these platforms forward the data to the FROST Server via the standardized SensorThings API, where it is stored in MongoDB. Meanwhile, the semantic building model of TUM in CityGML LOD 3.0 is processed with FME and converted into Cesium-compatible 3D Tiles. Finally, JavaScript is used to fetch live or historical data from the FROST Server and MongoDB, integrating it into Cesium 3D visualizations and interactive dashboards for end-user applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling Duration and Target Dates – Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This experimental report is part of the System-Theoretical Principles of Project Management course, focusing on how system-theoretical methods can be applied to analyze project scheduling and verify the impact of different strategies on project duration and resource allocation. We began by modeling project activities as a causal network and conducting scheduling analysis to identify the critical path and overall project duration, which served as the baseline for subsequent scenario comparisons. We then designed and compared three different scheduling strategies to examine how variations in resource allocation influence project duration and constrained conditions. Finally, we simulated different scheduling flexibility settings by adjusting the strength of boundary conditions to observe the effects of task concentration versus dispersion, thereby exploring their impact on project stability and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFC Model Checking Tasks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This task focuses on checking and validating an IFC model of a three-story office building. Students will apply BIM quality assurance methods using professional checking tools to detect design issues and propose effective improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj12-1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1. Model Checking in Solibri&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;checking-tasks&#34;&gt;Checking Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;door-clearance-check&#34;&gt;Door Clearance Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detect doors where clearance requirements are not fulfilled due to nearby furniture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suggest repositioning or resizing furniture to restore accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;window-area-ratio-check&#34;&gt;Window Area Ratio Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ensure window-to-space area ratio does not exceed 50% in office spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adjust window sizing or space planning to meet the requirement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;space-accessibility-check&#34;&gt;Space Accessibility Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify office spaces that are completely inaccessible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provide alternative circulation or openings to ensure accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;space-area-check&#34;&gt;Space Area Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check confidential meeting rooms smaller than 5 m².&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increase room size to comply with functional requirements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrong-property-set-check&#34;&gt;Wrong Property Set Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detect inner walls incorrectly marked as external (&lt;code&gt;IsExternal = true&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Correct property assignment for accurate building envelope definition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ifc-model-checking-report&#34;&gt;IFC Model Checking Report&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34; &#xD;&#xA;     style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5rem; max-width: 1200px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-left: 2rem; padding-right: 2rem; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;!-- iframe  --&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/Solibri.pdf&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          width=&#34;100%&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          height=&#34;600px&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          style=&#34;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 8px;&#34;&#xD;&#xA;          title=&#34;Solibri Report PDF&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Your browser does not support PDF preview. Please &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/Solibri.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;click here to download the full Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terra Vein</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project was carried out in collaboration with &lt;a href=&#34;https://xrhub-bavaria.de/&#34;&gt;XR HUB Bavaria&lt;/a&gt;, focusing on the production of an animation themed around future energy. The final work was showcased in the dome theater at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.1e9.community/festival-der-zukunft/2025/deutsch&#34;&gt;1E9 &amp;amp; Festival der Zukunft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj4.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Demo Animation&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1cmBN1STj06-iLnF-wBkBNgyE_9a5LTmO/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Open Full Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;geothermal-energy&#34;&gt;Geothermal Energy&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unlike solar or wind, geothermal energy reveals itself in a tangible way—rising as steam from beneath the Earth, a direct expression of its deep heat. It’s not only a sustainable choice but also a profound connection to the planet’s elemental forces. Our vision contrasts the soft, ethereal plumes of steam with the structured pipes that carry it—symbolizing harmony between nature and engineering. Geothermal represents a livable, powerful rhythm of the Earth, shaping a future where cities breathe in sync with nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIM.Fundamentals Modeling Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is the core practical assignment for the &amp;ldquo;BIM.Fundamentals&amp;rdquo; course in the Summer Term 2025 at the Technical University of Munich (TUM), School of Engineering and Design. The project aims to deeply explore the potential of Building Information Modeling (BIM) and to master the IFC data schema.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This task requires the creation of a detailed, semantically enriched BIM model that adheres to specific shape requirements. The model&amp;rsquo;s structure, appearance, and material definitions must be strictly defined, ensuring semantic accuracy and data consistency throughout the development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraints Design in Timber Modular Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project was developed during the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackaec.com/events.html&#34;&gt;2024 AEC Hackathon Munich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and collabrated with  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tum-venture-labs.de/labs/built-environment/&#34;&gt;TUM Venture Lab Built Environment&lt;/a&gt;. We proposed a &lt;strong&gt;Constraint Design (CD)&lt;/strong&gt; model, introducing an intermediate abstract layer that integrates manufacturing and MEP requirements early in the design phase. By embedding constraints upfront, the approach reduces redesign efforts, improves collaboration and efficiency..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hackathon-topics&#34;&gt;Hackathon Topics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The challenge from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dreso.com/de/&#34;&gt;Drees &amp;amp; Sommer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focused on timber modular design, where misaligned details between designers and manufacturers often cause costly redesigns. Our goal was to create an &lt;strong&gt;abstract intermediate model&lt;/strong&gt; that simplifies data exchange and coordination.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj6-6.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1. Overview of the main challenge (sourced from Drees &amp;amp; Sommer)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Portfolio-Interwoven Space</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project10/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This portfolio showcases my efforts to bridge architecture with interior design. They are not merely functional areas but storytelling venues, where every detail captivates and educates us about society, culture, and the environment. These works reflect my belief that creating spaces that not only integrate internally and externally but also provoke thought and evoke emotions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This portfolio is a reflection upon my design practice, displaying how a profound understanding of light, texture, and innovative technologies can be used to create spaces that are both beautiful and meaningful. It is a declaration of the values I hold dear: a design philosophy that emphasizes the narrative power of spaces, social engagement, and a deep respect for the land, while embracing digital innovation to address the challenges of the built environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 CAAD Workshop - RhinoVAULT Application</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This workshop introduces the role of digital technology in contemporary architecture, focusing on the development and application of CAD/CAM tools, vibrating knife systems, and CNC technology. Participants will first explore the theoretical foundations, including how these tools transform the architectural design process. They will then gain hands-on experience, from CAD-based part design to operating vibrating knife and CNC machines for model making, working in groups to create small-scale structural prototypes. Finally, the workshop examines real-world cases, current challenges, and future trends, encouraging innovative thinking, critical discussion, and strategies for integrating digital fabrication technologies into architectural practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Thatch Resort</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project situated in the heart of Taoyuan’s agricultural district. Designed with sustainability in mind, it utilizes local materials such as bamboo and rice straw, reflecting the surrounding landscape of rice fields. The resort’s architecture seamlessly blends with the natural environment, providing guests with a tranquil and authentic rural experience.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34; &#xD;&#xA;     style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 1rem; margin: 1rem auto; width: 100%; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-5.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 4px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-6.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 4px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34; &#xD;&#xA;     style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 1rem; margin: 1rem auto; width: 100%; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-7.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 4px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-8.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 4px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34; &#xD;&#xA;     style=&#34;display: flex; gap: 1rem; margin: 1rem auto; width: 80%; justify-content: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-9.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 8px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p style=&#34;color: gray; font-style: italic; font-size: 0.875rem; margin-top: 0.5rem; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      Figure 1. Site Plan&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;div style=&#34;flex: 1; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj11-10.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34; style=&#34;width:100%; border-radius: 8px;&#34; /&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p style=&#34;color: gray; font-style: italic; font-size: 0.875rem; margin-top: 0.5rem; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;      Figure 2. Explored View&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2021 CAAD Workshop - KUKA Robotic Arm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the “KUKA Robotic Arm Workshop,” participants will learn to set up and operate a KUKA robotic arm, focusing on essential safety and operational guidelines. The workshop includes an introduction to basic programming, allowing attendees to understand and manipulate the arm’s controls.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A key feature of the session is a hands-on exercise in robotic weaving, showcasing the arm’s precision and potential in digital manufacturing and design. This concise yet comprehensive workshop is an ideal introduction to the possibilities of robotic automation in creative and industrial applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
