<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Robotics on PEILING SONG</title><link>https://peilingsong.org/tags/robotics/</link><description>Recent content in Robotics on PEILING SONG</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 22:08:07 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peilingsong.org/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real-Time Building Digital Model Reconstruction Using a Robotic Agent</title><link>https://peilingsong.org/projects/project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilingsong.org/projects/project1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is designed to capture and process real-time spatial data of the built environment by integrating advanced sensing technologies, such as LiDAR and an RGB-D camera, onto a robotic platform. These sensors work in unison to collect high-quality spatial and visual data, which is then seamlessly streamed using the Robot Operating System (ROS). ROS facilitates the efficient handling of sensor data, enabling real-time processing through advanced algorithms that reconstruct the environment&amp;rsquo;s geometry with precision. By combining robotics, state-of-the-art sensors, advanced point cloud processing techniques, and real-time computation, the project aims to provide accurate and dynamic spatial mapping solutions, offering a robust foundation for applications in fields such as architecture, urban planning, and autonomous navigation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>2021 CAAD Workshop - KUKA Robotic Arm</title><link>https://peilingsong.org/projects/project9/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://peilingsong.org/projects/project9/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the “KUKA Robotic Arm Workshop,” participants will learn to set up and operate a KUKA robotic arm, focusing on essential safety and operational guidelines. The workshop includes an introduction to basic programming, allowing attendees to understand and manipulate the arm’s controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key feature of the session is a hands-on exercise in robotic weaving, showcasing the arm’s precision and potential in digital manufacturing and design. This concise yet comprehensive workshop is an ideal introduction to the possibilities of robotic automation in creative and industrial applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>