<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>BIM on PEILING SONG</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/bim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in BIM on PEILING SONG</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/bim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Twin × BIM × IoT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/blog1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the field of architecture, &lt;strong&gt;“comfort” and “energy efficiency” are often seen as conflicting goals&lt;/strong&gt;. Heating, Ventilation, and Air Conditioning (HVAC) systems account for nearly &lt;strong&gt;40% of a building’s total energy use&lt;/strong&gt;. Reducing energy consumption without compromising occupant comfort is therefore a complex and urgent challenge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently read and reviewed a study on a &lt;strong&gt;Digital Twin (DT) + BIM + IoT framework&lt;/strong&gt;, where the key focus was:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;➔ How to dynamically optimize indoor thermal comfort while reducing energy consumption through open-source platforms, real-time sensing, and machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Indoor Ambient Monitoring</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is about developing an Indoor Ambient Monitoring system to manage and visualize human comfort relevant environmental parameters like temperature, humidity, illuminance, noise level, CO2 concentration, and others in an indoor environment. Further, the task is to study an insight on LoRaWAN Indoor Network Coverage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj2-1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://xmruuu.github.io/25SS_IoT_Indoor-Ambient-Monitoring/&#34;&gt;Open Dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The system architecture is divided into hardware and software components. On the hardware side, multiple indoor environmental sensors (measuring CO, PM2.5, temperature, humidity, etc.) transmit data via LoRa using the CayenneLPP encoding format through a LoRaWAN gateway to IoT cloud platforms such as TTN and SWM. On the software side, these platforms forward the data to the FROST Server via the standardized SensorThings API, where it is stored in MongoDB. Meanwhile, the semantic building model of TUM in CityGML LOD 3.0 is processed with FME and converted into Cesium-compatible 3D Tiles. Finally, JavaScript is used to fetch live or historical data from the FROST Server and MongoDB, integrating it into Cesium 3D visualizations and interactive dashboards for end-user applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IFC Model Checking Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This task focuses on checking and validating an IFC model of a three-story office building. Students will apply BIM quality assurance methods using professional checking tools to detect design issues and propose effective improvements.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj12-1.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1. Model Checking in Solibri&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;checking-tasks&#34;&gt;Checking Tasks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;door-clearance-check&#34;&gt;Door Clearance Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detect doors where clearance requirements are not fulfilled due to nearby furniture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Suggest repositioning or resizing furniture to restore accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;window-area-ratio-check&#34;&gt;Window Area Ratio Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ensure window-to-space area ratio does not exceed 50% in office spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adjust window sizing or space planning to meet the requirement.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;space-accessibility-check&#34;&gt;Space Accessibility Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify office spaces that are completely inaccessible.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provide alternative circulation or openings to ensure accessibility.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;space-area-check&#34;&gt;Space Area Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Check confidential meeting rooms smaller than 5 m².&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increase room size to comply with functional requirements.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;wrong-property-set-check&#34;&gt;Wrong Property Set Check&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Detect inner walls incorrectly marked as external (&lt;code&gt;IsExternal = true&lt;/code&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Correct property assignment for accurate building envelope definition.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ifc-model-checking-report&#34;&gt;IFC Model Checking Report&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;not-prose&#34; &#xD;&#xA;     style=&#34;margin-top: 0.5rem; max-width: 1200px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; padding-left: 2rem; padding-right: 2rem; width: 100%;&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;!-- iframe  --&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;iframe src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/Solibri.pdf&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          width=&#34;100%&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          height=&#34;600px&#34; &#xD;&#xA;          style=&#34;border: 1px solid #ddd; border-radius: 8px;&#34;&#xD;&#xA;          title=&#34;Solibri Report PDF&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;Your browser does not support PDF preview. Please &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/documents/Solibri.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;click here to download the full Report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BIM.Fundamentals Modeling Task</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project is the core practical assignment for the &amp;ldquo;BIM.Fundamentals&amp;rdquo; course in the Summer Term 2025 at the Technical University of Munich (TUM), School of Engineering and Design. The project aims to deeply explore the potential of Building Information Modeling (BIM) and to master the IFC data schema.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This task requires the creation of a detailed, semantically enriched BIM model that adheres to specific shape requirements. The model&amp;rsquo;s structure, appearance, and material definitions must be strictly defined, ensuring semantic accuracy and data consistency throughout the development process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constraints Design in Timber Modular Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/project6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/project6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project was developed during the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hackaec.com/events.html&#34;&gt;2024 AEC Hackathon Munich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and collabrated with  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tum-venture-labs.de/labs/built-environment/&#34;&gt;TUM Venture Lab Built Environment&lt;/a&gt;. We proposed a &lt;strong&gt;Constraint Design (CD)&lt;/strong&gt; model, introducing an intermediate abstract layer that integrates manufacturing and MEP requirements early in the design phase. By embedding constraints upfront, the approach reduces redesign efforts, improves collaboration and efficiency..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;hackathon-topics&#34;&gt;Hackathon Topics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The challenge from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dreso.com/de/&#34;&gt;Drees &amp;amp; Sommer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; focused on timber modular design, where misaligned details between designers and manufacturers often cause costly redesigns. Our goal was to create an &lt;strong&gt;abstract intermediate model&lt;/strong&gt; that simplifies data exchange and coordination.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/pj6-6.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Dashboard&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Figure 1. Overview of the main challenge (sourced from Drees &amp;amp; Sommer)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
